Michael Olaniyan

09090529118 | Olaniyanmichael0@gmail.com | Lagos island, Lagos

Summary

A passionate Frontend engineer specialized in crafting user-friendly, responsive and visually appealing web and mobile applications. with a solid foundation in relevant technologies, I excel in bringing design concepts into interactive web and mobile experiences.

Enthusiastic about staying up-to-date with the latest frontend technologies and trends to deliver the best solutions.

Experience

Fiverr/Upwork | Lagos island, Lagos Website developer | 10/2022 - Present

- Maintained clear and open communication with clients throughout the project lifecycle, resulting in accurate alignment of expectations, reduced revisions and increased client satisfaction.
- Delivered pixel perfect UI designs according to clients needs and specifications.

Blueprints Pathway | Lekki, Lagos Front End Developer | 10/2022 - Present

- Implemented responsive design for optimal user experience across all devices.
- Improved load times by optimizing images and using performance techniques.
- collaborated with the team to improve user experience and interactivity on an existing Escrow application.

UMscope | Victoria Island, Lagos Front End Developer Intern | 02/2021 - 12/2021

- Assisted in building beautiful and responsive user interfaces.
- Learned and applied Agile methodologies and principles
- Gained hands-on-experience with version control using git and github.

Skills

React.js, React Native, JavaScript, Redux, Restful api, Axios, TailwindCSS, CSS Animations, CSS, HTML, Responsive Design, Cross-Browser Compatibility, Version Control/Git, Command Line/CLI

Education

National Open University | Lagos island, Lagos Bachelor of Science in Computer Science | 12/2024

GOMYCODE | ikoyi, Lagos Web developement | 04/2022

Graduated as the best web development student in GOMYCODE Nigeria.

Boys' Senior Academy | Lagos island, Lagos Secondary school | 09/2015